Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection AIA.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- I: Newspapers, 1836-2018; 238849
  - The Phoenix (New York), 1859-1861; cuid14753; 190671 (Box 185, Reel R-7943)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Digital access to The Phoenix is available through the University of Missouri Digital Library: http://dl.mospace.umsystem.edu/mu/islandora/object/mu%3A1249
    Custodial History
    The physical copy of The Phoenix in Box 185 was donated to the archives by Sean Prendiville and separated from his personal papers (AIA 005).
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Due to the fragility of the physical copy of this publication, researchers must use either the microfilm or online version before requesting the original.
  - Plain Dealer "PD Action Tab", Mar 1973; cuid14754; 190690 (Box 145)
  - San Francisco Gael, Feb 1993–Mar 1994; cuid14755; 190689 (Box 145)
  - Saoirse (Irish Freedom)(Dublin) (with gaps), May-Oct 1972, May 1987–Oct 1998, Jan 2005-Jun 2011; cuid14756; 190686 (Box 183)
  - Shamrock News, Mar 1976; cuid14757; 190688 (Box 145)
  - Shamrock Newspaper (NY), 1811; cuid14758; 190670 (Box 158)
  - South Boston On-Line Print Edition, Jul 2001; cuid14759; 190687 (Box 145)
  - Sovereign Nation (Dublin), Oct 1998, Aug 2001; cuid14760; 190685 (Box 145)
  - Tablet (Queens and Brooklyn, NY), Mar 1996; cuid14761; 190684 (Box 145)
  - Threshold, Sep 1981; cuid14762; 452596 (Box 145)
  - Tom Mannion Travel Supplement, Feb 1985; cuid14763; 190692 (Box 145)
  - TWU Express, Dec 1963; cuid14764; 590646 (Flat-file-folder 2 Left)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), 1955–1961; cuid14765; 190669 (Box 149)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), Aug 1971-May 1972; cuid14766; 190683 (Box 149)
- II: Periodicals, 1881-2008; 238856
  - Ais Eiri: The Magazine of Irish-America, 1979-1981; cuid14767; 280938 (Box 160, Folder 1A)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1963-1964, 1966-1968, 1970; cuid14768; 238857 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1971-1976; cuid14769; 238858 (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1977-1979; cuid14770; 238859 (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - American Gael, 1992-1999; cuid14771; 238868 (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1993-1997; cuid14772; 238975 (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1998-1999; cuid14773; 238976 (Box 160, Folder 5A)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, Feb 2000-Jul 2000; cuid14774; 238867 (Box 160, Folder 5B)
  - American Journal of Gaelic Culture (Chicago), 1996-1997; cuid14775; 351609 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soulis, Inc. - Newsletter - Litir Nuacht, 1971-1977; cuid14776; 238869 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - Sword of Light,The Irish American Review, 1974; cuid14777; 238870 (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc.- Ais-Eiri The Magazine of Irish America, Win 1979-Spr 1982; cuid14778; 238871 (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1982-1983; cuid14779; 238872 (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1984-1985; cuid14780; 238873 (Box 160, Folder 10)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1986; cuid14781; 238874 (Box 160, Folder 11)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1987; cuid14782; 238875 (Box 160, Folder 12)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1990-1992; cuid14783; 238876 (Box 160, Folder 13)
  - An Doras, 1996-1998; cuid14784; 238878 (Box 160, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1881, 1886-1889; cuid14785; 238879 (Box 166, Folder 10)
  - An Gaodhal, 1890; cuid14786; 238880 (Box 166, Folder 11)
  - An Gaodhal, 1891, 1893-1894; cuid14787; 238881 (Box 166, Folder 12)
  - An Gaodhal, 1893-1894 (Box 219, Folder 1)
  - An Gaodhal, 1896; cuid14788; 238882 (Box 166, Folder 13)
  - An Gaodhal, 1897-1899; cuid14789; 238883 (Box 166, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1901 (Box 219, Folder 2)
  - An Gaodhal, 1900-1902; cuid14790; 238884 (Box 166, Folder 15)
  - Bard, The, 1996-1999; cuid14791; 238885 (Box 160, Folder 15)
  - Beyond Ben Bulben (Australia), 1996-1997; cuid14792; 238886 (Box 160, Folder 16)
  - Bonded Shores, 1994-2000; cuid14793; 238887 (Box 160, Folder 17)
  - The Bridge: An Droichead, 1986-1987; cuid14794; 238888 (Box 160, Folder 18)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1977-1981; cuid14795; 238889 (Box 160, Folder 19)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1982-2008; cuid14796; 238890 (Box 160, Folder 20)
  - Carn: A Link Between Celtic Nations, 1974-1978; cuid14797; 238891 (Box 160, Folder 21)
  - Celtic News Service, 1975-1977, 1992-1996; cuid14798; 238892 (Box 160, Folder 22)
  - Celtic Renewal, 1995; cuid14799; 238893 (Box 160, Folder 23)
  - Cois na Farraige, 1984; cuid14800; 238894 (Box 160, Folder 24)
  - Desert Shamrock, 1994; cuid14801; 238895 (Box 160, Folder 25)
  - Ducas, 1971-1981 with gaps; cuid14802; 238896 (Box 161, Folder 26)
  - Ducas, 1985-2002; cuid14803; 238897 (Box 161, Folder 27)
  - Eire Ireland, 1963-1968; cuid14804; 238901 (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Eire Ireland, 1969-1973; cuid14805; 238902 (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Everyman, 1994-1995; cuid14806; 238903 (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Gaelic Journal, 1900; cuid14807; 238904 (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Gander, 1993-1997; cuid14808; 238905 (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Gander, 1998-1999; cuid14809; 238906 (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - Gander, 1999-2001, 2002, 2004; cuid14810; 238907 (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Harp: "Voice of the Irish Impression", Jun 1988; cuid14811; 238908 (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Here's Me Bus!, 1995-1996; cuid14812; 238909 (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Hibernian Life (Minneapolis, MN): vol. ii, no. 3, Jul-Sep 1989; cuid14813; 452599 (Box 166, Folder 16)
  - Holy Cross Quarterl y: The Irish Issue, Vol. 6, Nos. 1-4. College of the Holy Cross, Worcester, MA., 1974; cuid14814; 280936 (Box 161, Folder 9A)
  - Hornpipe: Irish Dance, Music and Culture in North America, 1999; cuid14815; 238910 (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Inside Ireland, 1984, 1999; cuid14816; 238911 (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, Mar 1966-Mar 1978; cuid14817; 238912 (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1984; cuid14818; 238913 (Box 161, Folder 13)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1985; cuid14819; 238914 (Box 161, Folder 14)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1986; cuid14820; 238915 (Box 161, Folder 15)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1987; cuid14821; 238916 (Box 161, Folder 16)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1988; cuid14822; 238917 (Box 161, Folder 17)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1989; cuid14823; 238918 (Box 161, Folder 18)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1990; cuid14824; 238919 (Box 161, Folder 19)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1991; cuid14825; 238920 (Box 162, Folder 20)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1992; cuid14826; 238921 (Box 162, Folder 21)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1993; cuid14827; 238922 (Box 162, Folder 22)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1994; cuid14828; 238923 (Box 162, Folder 23)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1995; cuid14829; 238924 (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1996; cuid14830; 238925 (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1997-1998; cuid14831; 238926 (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1999; cuid14832; 238927 (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 2000-2001; cuid14833; 238928 (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, 1985, undated; cuid14834; 238929 (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - Irish America, Jan 1986-Apr 1986; cuid14835; 238930 (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Irish America, May 1986-Dec 1986; cuid14836; 238931 (Box 162, Folder 8)
  - Irish America, 1987; cuid14837; 238932 (Box 162, Folder 9, Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 21)
  - Irish America, 1988; cuid14838; 238933 (Box 162, Folder 10)
  - Irish America, 1989; cuid14839; 238934 (Box 162, Folder 11)
  - Irish America, 1990; cuid14840; 238935 (Box 162, Folder 12)
  - Irish America, 1991; cuid14841; 238936 (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Irish America, 1992; cuid14842; 238937 (Box 163, Folder 14)
  - Irish America, 1993; cuid14843; 238938 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Irish America, Jan 1994-Jun 1994; cuid14844; 238939 (Box 163, Folder 2)
  - Irish America, Jan 1994-Aug 1994; cuid14845; 238940 (Box 163, Folder 3)
  - Irish America, Jan 1995-Aug 1995; cuid14846; 238941 (Box 163, Folder 4)
  - Irish America, Sep 1995-Dec 1995; cuid14847; 238942 (Box 163, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, Jan 1996-Apr 1996; cuid14848; 238943 (Box 163, Folder 6)
  - Irish America, May 1996-Dec 1996; cuid14849; 238944 (Box 163, Folder 7)
  - Irish America, 1997; cuid14850; 238945 (Box 163, Folder 8)
  - Irish America, Mar 1998-Aug 1998; cuid14851; 238946 (Box 163, Folder 9)
  - Irish America, Sep 1998-Dec 1998; cuid14852; 238947 (Box 163, Folder 10)
  - Irish America, Feb 1999-Jul 1999; cuid14853; 238948 (Box 163, Folder 11)
  - Irish America, Aug 1999-Nov 1999; cuid14854; 238949 (Box 163, Folder 12)
  - Irish America, Jan 2000-Mar 2000; cuid14855; 238950 (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Irish America, May 2000; cuid14856; 238951 (Box 163, Folder 14)
  - Irish America, Aug 2000-Nov 2000; cuid14857; 238952 (Box 163, Folder 15)
  - Irish America, Dec 2000-May 2001; cuid14858; 238953 (Box 164, Folder 16)
  - Irish America, Jun 2001-Nov 2001; cuid14859; 238954 (Box 164, Folder 17)
  - Irish America, Feb 2002-Nov 2002; cuid14860; 238955 (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Irish America, Jan 2003-Nov 2003; cuid14861; 238956 (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - Irish America, Jan 2004-May 2004; cuid14862; 238957 (Box 164, Folder 3)
  - Irish America, Jun 2004-Sep 2004; cuid14863; 238958 (Box 164, Folder 4)
  - Irish America, Jan 2005-Jul 2005; cuid14864; 238959 (Box 164, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, Dec 2010-Jan 2011; cuid14865; 351608 (Box 164, Folder 5A)
  - Irish American Post Magazine, 1997; cuid14866; 238960 (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - Irish American Voice, 1984; cuid14867; 238961 (Box 164, Folder 7)
  - Irish American Voice, 1985; cuid14868; 238962 (Box 164, Folder 8)
  - Irish American Voice, 1986; cuid14869; 238963 (Box 164, Folder 9)
  - Irish American Voice, 1987; cuid14870; 238964 (Box 164, Folder 10)
  - Irish at Home and Abroad, 1993-1995; cuid14871; 238965 (Box 164, Folder 11)
  - Irish Connections, 2001; cuid14919 (Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 21)
  - Irish Dancer, 1998; cuid14872; 238966 (Box 164, Folder 12)
  - IE: A Supplement to the Irish Echo, 1996-1998; cuid14873; 238967 (Box 164, Folder 13)
  - Irish People (Chicago) Vol. 1, nos. 5-6, 8-12; Vol 2. nos. 5,9,11; Vol 3. no. 1 (also available on microfilm in Tamiment), Oct 1923-Jan 1933 with gaps; cuid14874; 238968 (Box 164, Folder 14)
  - The Irish Republican Guard: Issues 3-5, 2009; cuid14875; 452600 (Box 166, Folder 17)
  - The Irish Review, 1937; cuid14920 (Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 21)
  - Irish Voice Magazine, 1954; cuid14876; 238969 (Box 164, Folder 15)
  - Irish Volunteer, 1991, 2000; cuid14877; 238970 (Box 164, Folder 16)
  - Keltoi: A Pan-Celtic Review, 1986-1987, 1990; cuid14878; 238971 (Box 164, Folder 17)
  - Lies of Our Times: British Terror in Northern Ireland, Oct 1990; cuid14879; 238972 (Box 164, Folder 18)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1985-1989; cuid14880; 238980 (Box 164, Folder 19)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1990; cuid14881; 238981 (Box 164, Folder 20)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1991; cuid14882; 238982 (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1992; cuid14883; 238983 (Box 165, Folder 2)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1993; cuid14884; 238984 (Box 165, Folder 3)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1994; cuid14885; 238985 (Box 165, Folder 4)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1995; cuid14886; 238986 (Box 165, Folder 5)
  - Nua Eabhrac, 1981-1981; cuid14887; 238974 (Box 165, Folder 6)
  - The Recorder: Bulletin of the American Irish Historical Society. (New York), 1932-1970, 1988; cuid14888; 355425; Holdings: 1932, Vol, 5, no. 5; 1933, Vol. 6, nos. 2-4; 1934, Vol. 7, nos. 1-3; 1935 Vol. 8, no. 1; 1936 Vol. 9, nos. 1-4; 1939 Vol. 10, no. 1-2, 6; 1950, Vol. 12, no. 1; 1951 Vol. 13, no. 1; 1952, Vol. 14; 1953 Vol. 15; 1954, Vol. 16; 1955 Vol. 16; 1963, Vol. 24; 1964, Vol. 26; 1965, Vol. 28; 1966, Vol. 29; 1967, Vol. 30; 1968, VOl. 31; 1970. Vol. 33; Supplesment to 1988 "In Memoriam Darcy O'Brien;" List of Publications, 1898-1943 [from 1952 on it looks like only one bulletin was published per annum] (Box 167)
    Scope and Content Note
    Holdings: 1932, Vol, 5, no. 5; 1933, Vol. 6, nos. 2-4; 1934, Vol. 7, nos. 1-3; 1935 Vol. 8, no. 1; 1936 Vol. 9, nos. 1-4; 1939 Vol. 10, no. 1-2, 6; 1950, Vol. 12, no. 1; 1951 Vol. 13, no. 1; 1952, Vol. 14; 1953 Vol. 15; 1954, Vol. 16; 1955 Vol. 16; 1963, Vol. 24; 1964, Vol. 26; 1965, Vol. 28; 1966, Vol. 29; 1967, Vol. 30; 1968, VOl. 31; 1970. Vol. 33; Supplesment to 1988 "In Memoriam Darcy O'Brien;" List of Publications, 1898-1943 [from 1952 on it looks like only one bulletin was published per annum]
  - Republican Bulletin / Iris na Poblachta (Dublin) Vol. 1, nos. 1-3, 1987; cuid14889; 351540 (Box 165, Folder 7)
  - Saoirse': Irish Freedom, 1987-1997; cuid14890; 238977 (Box 165, Folder 8)
  - Shamrock Leaf, 1990-1996; cuid14891; 238978 (Box 165, Folder 9)
  - Shanachie, The, 1990-2000; cuid14892; 238979 (Box 165, Folder 10)
  - Spirit of Freedom, 1986-1987; cuid14893; 238987 (Box 165, Folder 11)
  - Spirit of Freedom, 1988; cuid14894; 238988 (Box 165, Folder 12)
  - Spirit of Freedom, 1989; cuid14895; 238989 (Box 165, Folder 13)
  - University College Dublin Alumni Newsletter, Jun 1989-Jan 1993; cuid14896; 238990 (Box 165, Folder 14)
  - University College Dublin Alumni Magazine, 1993-1994; cuid14897; 238991 (Box 165, Folder 15)
  - University College Dublin Alumni Magazine, 1995-2000; cuid14898; 238992 (Box 165, Folder 16)
  - World of Hibernia, 1995; cuid14899; 238993 (Box 165, Folder 17)
  - World of Hibernia, 1995-1996; cuid14900; 238994 (Box 165, Folder 18)
  - World of Hibernia, 1996; cuid14901; 238995 (Box 165, Folder 19)
  - World of Hibernia, 1996-1997; cuid14902; 238996 (Box 165, Folder 20)
  - World of Hibernia, 1997; cuid14903; 238997 (Box 166, Folder 1)
  - World of Hibernia, Spr 1998; cuid14904; 238998 (Box 166, Folder 2)
  - World of Hibernia, Sum 1998-Aut 1998; cuid14905; 238999 (Box 166, Folder 3)
  - World of Hibernia, 1998-1999; cuid14906; 239000 (Box 166, Folder 4)
  - World of Hibernia, 1999; cuid14907; 239001 (Box 166, Folder 5)
  - World of Hibernia, Spr 2000; cuid14908; 239002 (Box 166, Folder 6)
  - World of Hibernia, Sum 2000-Win 2000; cuid14909; 239003 (Box 166, Folder 7)
  - World of Hibernia, Spr 2001; cuid14910; 239004 (Box 166, Folder 8)
  - World of Hibernia, Win 2001; cuid14911; 239005 (Box 166, Folder 9)